he is me as a beginner on rings by mastering
the basics I was able to get stronger and
so can you learn how to start color snacks
the smart way and progress at your own pace
keep watching to learn your first pull up and
Beyond assisted reps are great for beginners the
lower difficulty allows complete control over
the pull-up your mental cue is to use the arms
a lot and the legs are little the reduced body
weight makes full range pull-ups possible and
allows you to build confidence as a calisthenics
beginner your mission is to make things harder
voluntarily we get out what we put in don't
cheat effort as it's only cheating yourself
make each rep count negatives are a game changer
for improving pull-ups because we're around 120
stronger lowering verse lifting this method is
foolproof for beginners the goal is to lower
smoothly through the pull-up in order to build
strength in Reverse you have to overcome the urge
to drop down quickly fight for every degree of the
negative this method is not easy that's why the
average person skips it negatives are mentally
and physically difficult growth is guaranteed
bands are a final beginner friendly progression
copy the exact technique that you're seeing Paul
with power and pause teaching our back muscles
to contract with conviction is good for strength
pausing at the top and bottom improves problem
parts of the pull-up the hang and the lockout
controlling the negative is not to be skipped
each time you lower smoothly you're transforming
the body say goodbye to sticking points and
weak pull-ups by applying sound technique cues
foreign
push-ups are possible for everyone adjusting
posture on calisthenics is the equivalent of
changing the weight on gym exercises to unlock
your first push-up or increased reps master the
basics first kneeling reduces body weight by
roughly 50 percent the short lever makes it
manageable to rep out quality push-ups on
the Rings throwing in some eccentrics is
a great stepping stone to get stronger for
people who find kneeling too easy but full
push-ups too hard bridge the gap like this
doing our push-up practice at a regression
helps us unlock ring push-ups with perfect
technique but what makes ring so damn hard
people who have a strong bench press still
quiver uncontrollably rings are a whole
different animal because of the unstable base
of support strength specificity is a principle
beginner should burn into their brains our body
gets good at what we repeatedly do which includes
skill of exercise and surface to get good
at push-ups on rings do push-ups on rings oh
this game the cat improves shoulder flexibility
this strange exercise has you hanging and moving
upside down the upper body stretch at the
shoulders is amazing and you'll fall in love
with the feeling the Casual Observer who sees
you spinning around is going to be in awe as
they admire you moving unconventionally learning
something which looks hard but actually isn't is
a great boost for beginners who can say no to
easy attention am I right skin the cat should
feel uncomfortable but not painful be sensible
and listen to your body use a range of motion
which suits your flexibility level always respect
the sensations and move mindfully using a pronated
grip is the safest approach for lowering risk of
injury skin the cat is affected because it builds
strength and flexibility weighted stretching
is a potent way to gain flexibility compared
to Gentle passive stretching thanks to moving our
body with muscular efforts the challenges reward
with flexibility which actually lasts take this
strength stretch at your own pace there's no rush
what matters is using good technique and being
patient whether you're doing the easiest or
hardest skin the cat have faith knowing
that the benefits are incoming expect the
shoulders to feel a Plus on movements such as
push-ups and dips after skinning the cut your
scapular mobility and surrounding muscles
are improving big time with this bad boy I
recommend doing reps followed by a static hold
this method increases full range flexibility
and it also gets you stronger in the Deep
stretch the old saying of use it or lose
its rings true skin the cat will have your
shoulders feeling Supple and strong for life
develop your pushing strength with dips
this exercise is a calisthenics compound
every beginner should do the chest shoulders and
triceps get a serious workout by progressing your
dip I promise your physique will level up and
the calisthenics Journey will be easier Rings
plus dips are a match made in heaven thanks to
the instability for everyone concerned about
shoulder pain Rings cause less discomfort
because they move freely the body can find
a pushing path which feels comfortable based on
your proportions and flexibility make each rep
count by locking out the top and lowering into
a deep dip band dips are a perfect way to build
volume and grow a stronger upper body we're
doing full range calisthenics using correct
technique and training in a difficulty
which suits our level please pause at the
bottom each rep this makes your muscles work
without the band helping too much I encourage
beginners to get really good at dips the size and
strength gained in the upper body will serve you
well when never beyond the basics even after
graduating Beyond beginner level keep doing
Basics dips should be featured in your workouts
in some way shape or form until the end of time
core training is worth doing for beginners ring
rollouts strengthen your anterior ab muscles
will this exercise give you a visible six-pack no
Aesthetics are displayed through diet and calorie
control rollouts do improve six-pack strength
spine anti-extension to be exact for everyone
who's struggling to keep correct posture while
working out roll outs are the remedy everyone
has done planks before we brace the body and
prevent the spine from sagging rollouts are
pretty much a moving plank we're getting the
same outcome I personally like training ABS in
motion it's more fun to move the body compared
to suffering in one spot rollout technique is
the same as planks hollow body and posterior
pelvic tilt keep pumping out rep after rep
until it starts burning as the great Muhammad
Ali once said that's when it starts counting
to make rollouts harder lengthen the lever by
extending our body potential noticeable and the
gains are greater your goal is to keep the body
in horizontal alignment with every rollout app
training is misleading it's harder than it seems
what feels like proper form is often incorrect
I'm always convinced my technique is perfect
in my head but the reality speaks a different
story after self-coaching I usually need to brace
harder and put more tension into every rep with
rollouts don't get lazy exaggerated effort with
big breath bracing seems to work better challenge
Yourself by choosing a height relative to
the ground which suits your strength level
improved core control and straight arm strength
are the reward for rolling out on the regular
build your back strength with bodyweight rows
I see a massive difference in beginners who
wrote versus those who don't newcomers who Skip
the row have less muscle less strength and they
lack fundamental movement mechanics if you
just get really good at rows many problems
won't be there Pull Up Performance improves for
free when rows are done regularly this exercise
trains the same muscles and movement pattern
back and biceps plus shoulder extension if
you want a thicker mid-back rows are unmatched
for gaining girth with technique please keep
the Torso stiff like a plank and let your
shoulder blades move freely throughout the
row like all things in life hard work pays off
doing rows until you can't move challenges you
to change rows are a worthy ring pool because
they are scalable from easy to less easy what
makes ringro's unique is they move around forcing
us to develop body control don't worry because
newbie gains are going to come fast with rose
after wrapping out rows consistently you'll
have the muscle mass and basic strength
you need to level up with calisthenics
foreign s are great for knee raises too this
exercise strengthens the ABS and hip flexors
make sure to breathe out and squeeze the stomach
hard this technique is key for getting a peak AB
contraction control the movement from your
muscles lowering down mindfully keeps things
strict and effective training the ABS is
worth the effort because it improves full
body strength the core acts as a link between
your upper and lower body helping with force
transfer a strong core gained from knee razors
will make you better at every exercise in your
workouts with ring support razors we kill
two birds with run Stone improve straight
arm strength and ab work by training the core
we're distracted from the difficulty of holding
the straight arm lock out by doing full range
knee raises the ab muscles will grow bigger
if you're looking to enhance Aesthetics knee
razors can add size to your six-pack foreign
holds up best for beginners spending time with
this exercise builds stability in your upper body
we're gaining what's called straight arm scapular
strength this is a fancy way of saying shoulders
which are ready for anything with practice you
will unlock Superior Body Control to stay still
on rings without a problem you'll notice the
lockout is featured in many gymnastics skills
although the advanced stuff is motivating this
tutorial is actually for beginners Let's Get
Back to Basics technique is simple keep the elbow
straight and turn the thumbs out shorter straps
are easier when learning so keep that in mind
but why do we need static holds they seem so
boring we're getting valuable time and attention
at the main point of weakness on rings instability
putting your full effort into improving weak
links is wise and it helps you improve faster
bulletproofing our body against aches pain and
injury is another important reason everyone
wants to skip steps and is then confused
why they aren't improving you can't enjoy
calisthenics if suffering with setbacks which
are caused by poor preparation the connective
tissues in your joints and tendons improve
with isometrics preparing you for the demands
of calisthenics including straight arm strength
gives a massive Advantage for beginners and sets
them up for Success here's today's exercises
listed by category in order of difficulty if
you want to continue progressing beyond the basics
watch this beginner video and get stronger sale